Hello! In this episode of Bug Bounty Reports
Explained I will show you a way to steal
documents and data of other users from Dropbox-owned
HelloSign application by exploiting an SSRF in
the integration with Google Drive. I am sure that
this bug is still present in many integrations out
there so make sure to stick until the end of the
video where I will show you how you should test
for this bug. Link to the original post, by Harsh,
also known as httpvoid, is in the description.
Enjoy! This episode is sponsored by Intigriti. Intigriti
is Europe's biggest bug bounty platform with over
400 programs to hack on. I hugely appreciate
Intigriti for investing a lot in community
enablement. They create an awesome bug bytes
newsletter, they create monthly XSS challenges,
they even have a great YouTube channel.
If you are not one of over 50,000 hunters,
check out Intigriti now using
the link from the description.
HelloSign is an application owned by Dropbox
that's used to sign documents. It also integrates
with Google Drive so you can ask someone to
sign a document that you store on your Google
Drive. HelloSign must somehow access files from
your drive. And there are a few ways to do this
integration but let's see how it worked in this
example. Of course, first, you must authenticate
to your Google account and authorize HelloSign to
access your files. Then, this iframe pops up with
the list of your files. When you finally choose
a file that you would like to sign, the iframe
sends a postMessage to HelloSign which contains
the file ID of the file that you've chosen.
Then, you send the request with this file
ID to HelloSign and HelloSign communicates
with Google Drive API to fetch this file on
the server and then serves you this file.
So HelloSign here acts as a proxy. And, of course,
I'm simplifying this process a bit. It takes a few
requests but there is nothing interesting or worth
mentioning in between the first and the last one.
But let's take a closer look at what actually
HelloSign server does to fetch this file. Before
the attack was successful, the hunter had to
assume these facts would we now know for certain.
This is Google Drive API endpoint to serve a
file. It contains the file ID which you had to
send to HelloSign server first. But this endpoint
does not respond directly with a file content.
It returns a JSON with metadata about the
file. This metadata contains the downloadUrl
which is an actual address to the file contents.
So HelloSign must make another request to this URL
to fetch the file which can
eventually be served to you.
So here HelloSign makes two requests and whenever
you have a functionality where the server makes
HTTP requests to the URL which you, at least
partially control, you should be thinking about
SSRFs - about the possibility to trick the server
into sending these requests to other locations.
And when we look at these two addresses, the
second one doesn't seem to be under our control at
all because we can't influence the URL where our
file is stored by Google Drive. The first one is a
bit better because at least we control the file ID
but unfortunately, it's not possible to trick the
server into sending this request to other host
if you only control the part after the slash.
What you can do, however, is
you can try to control the path
and parameters of the request. So let's take
a look at the reference of this endpoint to
see if there's anything that could give us, for
example, an open redirect. At the first sight,
it doesn't look like so. None of these
parameters looks to be particularly interesting.
However, when we scroll back to the top, we
can see a mention of the alt=media parameter.
When it's provided, the server doesn't return a
JSON with metadata about the file but it returns
the file itself. If HelloSign application would
use this parameter, they wouldn't have to make
two requests to first fetch the metadata and
then fetch the file but they could fetch the
file with a single request. So let's think
about what would happen if we would inject
this parameter into the file ID and
it would not be encoded properly.
The server would return a whole file
to the first request by HelloSign.
But HelloSign would not know about it and it
would try to parse JSON thinking it's metadata.
So all you could do with an image or a pdf is to
force a JSON parsing error - nothing interesting.
But if you do this to an actual valid JSON,
then HelloSign will try to parse this JSON,
extract things like the title
and other metadata from the file,
and most importantly, it would also extract the
downloadUrl and send a request to this address
to then fetch you the response. So this is
a full-read SSRF. You can trick the server
into sending requests to arbitrary locations
and the server gives you the response.
What's the impact of this? The HelloSign
application is hosted on AWS. You can use the
metadata URL which contains AWS credentials
which you can use to log in to the server.
From there, you have multiple ways to steal
data of other users of HelloSign application.
That's why this vulnerability was classified
as critical and rewarded over $17,500.
Note the fact that Google
Drive API was not vulnerable.
It behaved exactly like its documentation says.
It's a bug in the integration. There are probably
thousands of applications that integrate with
Google Drive. A part of them uses the same flow
that HelloSign application used and a part of
this surely is still vulnerable to this attack.
So whenever you see an application that works
like this - that it takes the file ID from you,
fetches the file on the server - you should
try adding alt=media parameter to the file ID
to see what happens. If you see an error,
particularly about JSON parsing, then it's a
good chance that you just found this SSRF. What
you should do then is you should prepare a JSON
that looks like a metadata about the file. For
that, refer to Google Drive API documentation.
If you want to learn even more about SSRFs, check
out this video about my report to Stripe. Already,
two people have watched this video
and found bypasses that I had missed
making $500 each. If you want to
see if you can find another one,
click the card on your screen right now. For now
that's all, thank you for watching and goodbye!